## Jeff O'Malley

San Juan Capistrano, California

Regional Sales Manager Western U.S. - Jenn-Air

#### Summary

23 years in the consumer durables industry. Sales and sales management with several Fortune 500 companies including Maytag, GE, Electrolux and Whirlpool.

Goals include being a director or vice president at a major consumer products company, utilizing my sales and marketing skills I have acquired over the years to lead a sales team and develop new and innovative products that consumers want to purchase.

Core Knowledge and Specialties: Sales, Wholesale, Marketing, Advertising, Sales Training, Budgeting, Hiring, Forecasting, Negotiating, New Customer Development, Product Development, Program Design, Inventory Management. Specialize in high end consumer goods, National sales execution plans, Influence product development and pipeline, National program development and negotiation, Executive relationship building, Expansion of Luxury Kitchen retailers, Marketing strategy development for luxury brands, Sales team leadership and development

## Experience

Southwest Regional Sales Manager - Jenn-Air at Whirlpool Corporation

July 2014 - Present (4 years 8 months)

Sales management of the Jenn-Air brand for CA, AZ, NV and HI.

## National Accounts Sales Manager Jenn-Air at Whirlpool Corporation

August 2012 - Present (6 years 7 months)

Manage top national customers to achieve aggressive sales growth of Jenn-Air brand luxury appliances. Develop marketing, advertising campaigns, and sales training programs to drive double-digit growth on a national level.

#### Accomplishments

- Promoted from Market Manager to National Sales Manager within two years of employment
- Grew two of the largest Jenn-Air customers to significant, national levels, including management of all individual locations
- · Negotiate national sales programs at an executive level
- Create national advertising, marketing, and promotional strategies
- Develop sales execution models to drive sales results through national customers

Western Regional Sales Manager at Jenn-Air January 2010 - Present (9 years 2 months)

#### Market Manager- Jenn-Air Brand at Whirlpool Corporation December 2009 - December 2011 (2 years 1 month)

Effectively managed and grew sales of the Jenn-Air luxury appliance brand through retail and contract distributors throughout the Southern California market through aggressive sales plans, training, and marketing efforts.

#### Accomplishments

- Re-positioned the newly designed luxury appliance brand of Jenn-Air in the Southern California market, resulting in over a 30% increase in sales each year to high end appliance retailers.
- Executed new marketing strategy that resulted in increased display presence, new dealer showrooms and increased advertising of the brand, all driving increased revenue and margin.
- Corporate Winner's Circle nominee and runner up for 2010 Jenn-Air Market Manager of the Year contest for top performers in the corporation.
- Developed customer programs tailored to their unique market niche that allowed substantial growth and partnerships.
- Created all aspects of dealer programming.

# Regional Sales Manager at Electrolux Major Appliances

2006 - 2009 (3 years)

Managed a \$35,000,000 sales region, including 4 district managers, over 150 customers and sold 5 different Electrolux brands within 7 major appliance product categories. Was responsible for monthly sales goals, advertising, promotional and program budgets and new business development

#### Accomplishments

- Increased total brand sales +11% YTD in 2008, increased profitability +46% through improved pricing and mix strategy and increased share growth while industry shipments were off -7%-10% vtd.
- Licensed over 20 new retail dealer customers in 2008 alone, adding over \$1,500,000 in new sales revenue.
- Successfully launched the new Electrolux luxury brand to the U.S. retail market with over 170 new models through a product launch program, sales training initiatives, and a massive advertising campaign.

#### Key Account Manager at General Electric Consumer and Industrial

2002 - 2006 (4 years)

Managed overall sales for three appliance brands with top National customer, Pacific Sales.

Conducted meetings with key management and presented sales and advertising programs to further develop sales growth. Trained sales and management on all products for each brand on a weekly basis. Developed an analyzed sales reports, as well as created strategies for sales growth.

#### Accomplishments

- Increased total sales in 2004 by 34% with Pacific Sales, a top ten dealer in the U.S.
- Grew high-end brands, Monogram +36% and Profile +49% in 2004 and increased margins by +24%.
- Executed over 140 new product introductions resulting in incremental growth.
- Coordinated over 150 live gourmet cooking demonstrations in 12 different store locations.
- Presented training information to over 800 local salespeople at the annual Training Expos.
- Developed a service program for Pacific Sales resulting in fewer service returns and faster service.

#### Sales Manager at Purcell Murray Company

2001 - 2002 (1 year)

Managed and led a team of 7 territory managers to achieve sales and marketing goals. Assisted in becoming the largest national, luxury appliance and plumbing distributor for the following brands: Bosch, Thermador, Gaggenau, Uline, Best, Broan, Franke, and La Cornue, grossing in record-high sales.

#### Accomplishments

- Significantly Grew sales of eight premium brands of appliance and plumbing products to major retailers and builder customers in Southern California.
- Grew sales by 26% within second year of employment
- Developed and negotiated dealer programs resulting in new customers and increased product commitments.
- Implemented successful sales training programs for customers using state of the art training and showroom facility

#### Key Account Manager at Maytag

1994 - 2000 (6 years)

Sales management for several large retail customers in both Houston TX and Los Angeles CA.

# Education

University of Tennessee, Knoxville BA, Liberal Arts, Business, 1988 - 1992

Activities and Societies: Alpha Tau Omega Fraternity

# Jeff O'Malley

San Juan Capistrano, California Regional Sales Manager Western U.S. - Jenn-Air



## 3 people have recommended Jeff

"Jeff is a forward looking manager who finds new and innovative ways to enhance customer experience. His people management skills are excellent and is a proven team leader."

—John White, CMO, AVB Inc., worked directly with Jeff at General Electric Consumer and Industrial

"I have known and worked with Jeff for 10 years. He has consistently excelled in each and every one of his endeavors, thriving in very competitive sales markets while successfully managing others to do the same. You would be hard pressed to find someone with more expertise in premium consumer goods."

-Rob Knenlein, Senior Key Account Manager, Electrolux, worked directly with Jeff at Maytag

"Jeff is an outstanding sales person and golfer."

—Chris O'Malley, SPHR, Recruiting Lead, J&J Talent Acquisition, Johnson & Johnson, was a consultant or contractor to Jeff at Electrolux Major Appliances

# John McDonough

New York, New York

Regional Builder Sales Manager at BSH Home Appliance

## Experience

Regional Builder Sales Manager at BSH Home Appliance

June 2006 - Present (12 years 9 months)

Responsible for the builder sales segment in the East region for BSH Home Appliances. Manage a sales team to reach growth targets in the contract sales division. Selling to both mufti family and single family builders, contractors and developers.

#### Education

**Purdue University** 

Business Management, Business, Management, Marketing, and Related Support Services, 1998 - 2001

# John McDonough

New York, New York

Regional Builder Sales Manager at BSH Home Appliance



#### Andrew Feldman

San Francisco Bay Area
Director of US Sales

#### Summary

Highly effective Sales and Merchandising Professional with extensive experience in Supply Chain Stability, Procurement, and Customer Management. Progressive expertise in planning and coordination of products, processes, scheduling, and vendor negotiations. Proven ability to successfully champion strategies to upper management; record of leadership, communication, and customer service skills. Committed to team work ethic with advanced communication skills in resolving problems and completing projects.

#### Experience

Director of US Sales - Appliance Channel at Onward Manufacturing Company February 2015 - Present (4 years 1 month)

Director of Outdoor & Seasonal at Brand Source April 2014 - January 2015 (10 months)

National Sales Manager at Expert Warehouse 2 November 2001 - April 2014 (12 years 6 months)

Consumer Electronics, Major Appliances, and Outdoor Living categories.

Supervise staff of 15 to support efforts in sales, purchasing, logistics, merchandising, category turnover, customer service escalations, and vendor relationships. Supervise team of 14 outside sales representatives in sales, logistics, programs, and extended warranties. Set pricing and promotional programs and create messaging/differentiators for products in stores.

#### Advertising Sales at Tailgater Monthly

August 2011 - November 2013 (2 years 4 months)

Tailgater Monthly Magazine (TGM) offers a unique look into the lifestyle of tailgating. RKD Media Partners, one of the founders of the magazine, provides marketing options in print, online, mobile, and at-event. The magazine reaches 220,000 readers via paid and digital circulation. My job consisted of promoting the magazine to manufacturers of the consumer electronics, major appliance, and furniture industries. The goal was to have them advertise in the magazine using my strong relationships and predetermined media kit provided by Tailgater Monthly. TGM gave me the freedom to think outside the normal procedures and offer more of a service to open up new categories and business for the magazine and manufacturers.

Sales Executive at ArchBrook Laguna

#### 2001 - 2009 (8 years)

Managed daily sales and operations of all internet business/e-commerce with various manufacturers. Supported independent consumer electronic accounts, met with clients, and interacted with vendors. Prepared purchase orders, estimates, and customer confirmations.

## Education

William Paterson University of New Jersey Bachelor, Sociology, 2002 - 2007

#### Andrew Feldman

San Francisco Bay Area Director of US Sales

# Linked in.

## 9 people have recommended Andrew

"I have worked right along with Andrew and his skills are fit for any business environment. His tenacity in managing tasks at hand are superb and always delivered results above and beyond of what was expected of him."

—Elvis Alvarez, President, Accutech Sales, worked directly with Andrew at ArchBrook Laguna

"Andrew was very detail oriented and sales driven. Andrew helped to introduce new opportunities to Stereo Advantage. Andrew is a pleasure to work with."

-Wesley Froebel, President, Minuteman Press Buffalo, was Andrew's client

"Andrew has amazing customer service skills and is on point to take care of details. He has a passion for what he does and does what he promises. There are very few people out there who you can count on to produce in business every single time with quality, promptness and do it with a great attitude and Andrew is one of those people. I very much enjoyed working with Andrew and hope that our paths cross again in the future. He would be an asset anywhere."

—Barrie McCorkle, Director of Supplier Programs, D-Tools Inc., was with another company when working with Andrew at Expert Warehouse 2

"Andrew is a true professional in his field and takes great care to make sure strategic objectives are attained."

—Barry Rothman, sales manager, key sales group, was a consultant or contractor to Andrew at Expert Warehouse 2

"I had the pleasure of working with Andrew when I.Lehrhoff & Company was on it's own. Then I worked with Andrew at ArchBrook Laguna when they purchased I.Lehrhoff & Company. Andrew knows his product and business. Excellent to deal with. I would not have made it at ArchBrook Laguna without Andrews assistance."

—Catherine Nemick, Finance, Aspire Technology Partners, worked with Andrew at Expert Warehouse 2

"Andrew gets results and has never met a wall he couldn't crash through in the interests of moving the business forward. Great attention to detail and always pushing the envelope to grow both personally and professionally."

—Dean Sottile, SVP Digital & Technology, Nationwide Marketing Group, managed Andrew at Expert Warehouse 2

"I met Andrew a few years ago as our companies worked together to start a business for the smaller independents in our industry. Andrew was a pleasure to work with during that process and had some great ideas of what to do differently. He thinks outside of the box and pushes his partners for new opportunities to promote the business. He also has a great sense of humor and is fun to work with because though you work hard you work together while having fun."

—Deena Ghazarian, Managing Partner, TargetPath LLC, was with another company when working with Andrew at Expert Warehouse 2

"Andrew is a passionate professional who is driven to understand his clients true needs and deliver on them beyond expectations."

—Dave Cohen, Executive Creative Director, INSPIRED Freelance, was with another company when working with Andrew at Expert Warehouse 2

"Andrew is a very proactive, thorough and responsive business partner. His ease of process integration and desire to maximize a business relationship to generate growth, sets him apart from many. He truly makes me feel like a partner - striving for common goals. He is always available and makes change happen. He is someone I would turn to, to "get things done"!"

—Sherry Clem, Key Account Sales - Home Appliances, LG Electronics, was with another company when working with Andrew at Expert Warehouse 2

#### Northeast Regional Sales Manager

## Experience

Northeast Regional Sales Manager at Dacor

June 2017 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Territory Sales Manager at Distinctive Appliance Distributing

July 2016 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Regional Sales Manger at Viking Range, LLC

January 2014 - Present (5 years 2 months)

Regional Sales Manager at Hadco

July 2012 - January 2013 (7 months)

District Sales Manager at Delia Inc.

December 1999 - June 2012 (12 years 7 months)

Store Manager at Seavey's Inc.

May 1989 - December 1999 (10 years 8 months)

#### Education

University of Maine

1985 - 1989



#### John Bonacci

Rochester, New York

Regional Sales Manager at Samsung Electronics America

#### Summary

Meticulous, dedicated sales professional with demonstrated leadership skills aimed at exceeding sales goals. Strong knowledge of territory management and market share growth along with great experience in handling sales analysis and reporting duties. My background includes extensive sales, management and product training in the wireless & home appliance industries.

#### Experience

# Regional Sales Manager, Home Appliances at Samsung Electronics America

November 2016 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Prospect, qualify, recruit and train Authorized Samsung Dealers in New York, Pennsylvania & Ohio. Assist dealers with inventory management, forecasting and placing orders.

Create effective marketing campaigns for dealers to increase their sales; including planning out direct mail, newspaper and social media campaigns.

Develop sales goals for existing dealers on areas of opportunity to maximize their business.

Train & support existing dealers on product line up & current promotions.

#### Area Sales Manager at Dish Network

August 2012 - November 2016 (4 years 4 months)

2015 Winner's Circle Recipient

2016--NorthEast Account Manager of the Month for January & February.

2015--Northeast Account Manager of the Month for October, November & December.

2014--Northeast Account Manager of the Month for May & December.

## Account Manager/Customer Service at Valtech Holdings

February 2011 - August 2012 (1 year 7 months)

Regional Manager at Sprint

October 2009 - February 2011 (1 year 5 months)

District Manager at Nextel Partners--NexGen Wireless, LLC

November 2003 - August 2009 (5 years 10 months)

# Education

Monroe Community College Associate's degree, Business Administration and Management, General, 1995 - 1999 Greece Olympia High School Diploma, 1991 - 1995

## John Bonacci

Rochester, New York

Regional Sales Manager at Samsung Electronics America



## 1 person has recommended John

"John has an excellent business acumen that promotes relationship building within his workforce. As my manager, John supported my development with sales skills and operations. He is a true asset to any business relationship. His years of sales management is evident when working with him on any project."

—Anthony Lutrario, Vice President, Director of Training & Development, M&T Insurance Agency, Inc., reported to John at Nextel Partners--NexGen Wireless, LLC